<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="./_c74_ref.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>

<c74object name="rapidmax">

	<digest>
		 A machine learning object for gesture-sound interaction design
	</digest>

	<description>
		A machine learning object that provides a set of supervised machine learning algorithms for gesture-sound interaction design. By implementing multilayer perceptron (MLP) artificial neural networks (ANN), it allows to train linear regression and k-nearest neighbour classification models between multiple dimensions of input and target output. 
	</description>

	<!--METADATA-->
	<metadatalist>
		<metadata name="author">Francesco Di Maggio, Atau Tanaka and Michael Zbyszyński</metadata>
		<metadata name="tag">Gesture-sound interaction design</metadata>
		<metadata name="tag">Interactive machine learning</metadata>
	</metadatalist>

	<!--INLETS-->
	<inletlist>
		<inlet id="0" type="list">
			<digest>(list) input a list of floats to a trained rapidmax object</digest>
		</inlet>
	</inletlist>

	<!--OUTLETS-->
	<outletlist>
		<outlet id="0" type="list">
			<digest>(list) output list prediction based on the trained model</digest>
		</outlet>
		<outlet id="1" type="list">
			<digest>(bang) training is done</digest>
		</outlet>
	</outletlist>

	<!--ARGUMENTS-->
	<objarglist>
		<objarg name="name">
			<digest>Name of the model: must be same as dict.</digest>
		</objarg>
	</objarglist>

	<!--MESSAGES-->
	<methodlist>
		<method name="regress">
			<arglist>
				<!-- <arg name="regress" optional="0" type="symbol" /> -->
			<arg name="regress" />
			</arglist>
			<digest>
				Train a neural network to predict values inbetween data points.
			</digest>
			<description>
				The message 'regress', followed by the name of a dict to which rapidmax adddress the holding training set data, will train a neural network to predict values inbetween data points.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="classify">
			<arglist />
				<arg name="classify"/>
			<arglist />
			<digest>
				Train a k-nearest neighbor classifier to predict the closest data point.
			</digest>
			<description>
				The message 'classify', followed by the name of a dict to which rapidmax adddress the holding training set data,will train a k-nearest neighbor classifier to predict the closest data point.
			</description>
		</method>
	</methodlist>

	<!--SEEALSO-->
	<seealsolist>
		<seealso name="GIMLeT.ml.ann"/>
	</seealsolist>

</c74object>
